<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Linux on Mhaziqrk Blog</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Mhaziqrk Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:20:12 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering Git Commands: A Developer's Guide</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2023/sept/git/masteringgitcommandsadevelopersguide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:34:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2023/sept/git/masteringgitcommandsadevelopersguide/</guid><description>Git is a powerful version control system that every developer should have in their toolkit. Whether you are working on a solo project or collaborating with a team, Git helps you track changes, manage versions, and collaborate seamlessly. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some essential Git commands that will help you become a Git pro.
Git Download What is Git? Git is a distributed version control system that was created by Linus Torvalds in 2005.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Git Commands: Part 2</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2023/sept/git/gitcommand2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:20:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2023/sept/git/gitcommand2/</guid><description>In the first part of our Git commands guide , we covered the basics of Git, from initializing a repository to pushing and pulling changes from remotes. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into some more advanced Git commands and concepts that will help you take your version control skills to the next level.
Git Branching Strategies Branching is a fundamental concept in Git, and understanding branching strategies can greatly improve your workflow, especially when collaborating with others.</description></item><item><title>Run Command in Background on Linux</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/run-command-in-background-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:11:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/run-command-in-background-linux/</guid><description>Tested on : Ubuntu Server 20.04 LTS
Today, I want to show you how to run linux command in background even the terminal close.
I will use rclone as example application to run in background. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult to run command in background. You just need to add &amp;amp; symbol and type disown command after the first command run in the background.
Example : rclone sync -P /mnt/disk4/pictures /mnt/disks/external/pictures &amp;gt; .</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Server - Laptop Lid Ignore</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/laptop-lid-ignore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:44:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/laptop-lid-ignore/</guid><description>Use Your Laptop As A Server Tested on : Ubuntu 20.04 LTS
To disable entering the sleep mode I had to edit the /etc/systemd/logind.conf file and modify the line:
Just uncomment the line by removing #
from this :
#HandleLidSwitch=suspend #LidSwitchIgnoreInhibited=no #HandleLidSwitchDocked=ignore to this :
HandleLidSwitch=ignore LidSwitchIgnoreInhibited=no HandleLidSwitchDocked=ignore Then restart the OS via:
sudo service systemd-logind restart Then you can close the laptop lid .</description></item><item><title>Protect Your Linux Server Against Hackers and Malware</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/protect-your-linux-server-against-hackers-and-malware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 21:11:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/protect-your-linux-server-against-hackers-and-malware/</guid><description>Copy from The Digital Life Blog Optimize your deployments to lower the attack surface, especially when you’re running administrative web interfaces and Docker Containers.
SECURITY IS NOT A SIMPLE CHECK-LIST First, I want to emphasize how important it is that you develop your own security strategy. Because when you search on the web about “How to protect Linux” or “Harden your Linux Server”, you’ll find tons of articles. People are just throwing out their “best practices” (just like this article here :).</description></item><item><title>Self Sign Cert</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/self-sign-cert/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 20:54:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/self-sign-cert/</guid><description>SSL Certificates Cheat-Sheet X.509 is an ITU standard defining the format of public key certificates. X.509 are used in TLS/SSL, which is the basis for HTTPS. An X.509 certificate binds an identity to a public key using a digital signature. A certificate contains an identity (hostname, organization, etc.) and a public key (RSA, DSA, ECDSA, ed25519, etc.), and is either signed by a Certificate Authority or is Self-Signed.
Self-Signed Certificates Generate CA Generate RSA openssl genrsa -aes256 -out ca-key.</description></item><item><title>Vimtutor - Tutorial for newbie Vim user</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/vimtutor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:57:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/vimtutor/</guid><description>Base On : VIM Tutor - Version 1.7 Copied version
Install vimtutor on Fedora 35 : sudo dnf install vim-enhanced
=============================================================================== = W e l c o m e t o t h e V I M T u t o r - Version 1.7 = =============================================================================== Vim is a very powerful editor that has many commands, too many to explain in a tutor such as this. This tutor is designed to describe enough of the commands that you will be able to easily use Vim as an all-purpose editor.</description></item><item><title>Setup Hugo</title><link>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/setup-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:38:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.mhaziqrk.uk/posts/2022/setup-hugo/</guid><description>Cara Setup Hugo Static Site di Github Pages Bahan ini disalin terus daripada website hackmd . Hanya tujuan rujukan semata-mata. Ada beberapa bahagian diubah. Tutorial boleh ditonton di youtube - Tutorial: Blogging with Hugo and GitHub Pages-Sarah Gibson Saya akan membawa anda melalui penciptaan tapak web anda sendiri, dihoskan pada GitHub Pages dan dibina dengan Hugo. Anda boleh melihat contoh tapaknya dipautkan di bawah.
website : https://mhaziqrk.uk (website ini) Repo : https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>